Ivan Filinkov Senior Technical Writer

Contact

Address Tbilisi Georgia

E-mail Ivan@filinkov.org

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/filinkov-ivan/

Skills

Verbal and Written communication

Excellent

Jira + EasyBi

Excellent

Public appearances

Very Good

Creating Diagrams

Very Good

Languages

Russian

Excellent

English

Good

Experienced technical writer with over 4 years of experience. I wrote user guides, reorganized the documentation process, by moving it to Jira. I also transferred documentation from Drupal 6 to Confluence.

2 years ago I've been promoted to Lead Technical Writer and tasked with creating team of 5 technical writers from scratch. In this role, I have hired and trained employees by writing instructions, holding webinars and recording video instructions. 1 employee from my team has been promoted to product analyst.

Work History

2018-12 -2023-03

Lead Technical Writer

r_keeper, Moscow

r_keeper is software company with the product, which is used in 65,000 restaurants in 55 countries.

- Created and managed team of 5 technical writers under agile methodology;
- Implemented Jira documentation process with cross validation and EasyBI reports;
- Established processes and text guidelines for whole company in order to ensuring consistency of texts produced;
- Writing and reviewing marketing texts for blog, email and social media;
- Created video tutorials and organized educational meetups.

2017-06 -2018-12

SEO Consultant

Freelance. Remote

- Creating Facebook Adv Manager and Google Adwords advertising
- Building semantic cores for sites
- Developing Telegram bots.

2013-02 -2017-05

L2 Support Engineer

Onlanta, Moscow

Onlanta is part of LANIT, Russia's largest IT company with 14.000 employees and 2,8 bln \$ revenue.

- Led team of 10 support engineers: 7 people on 1L and 3 people on 2L. Setting goals, supervision, professional development management, KPIs. Customer troubleshooting;
- Administered 3 corporate sites: knowledge base, Redmine and VCS system. Generated reports via SQL;
- Created knowledge base process and instructions which helped to reduce tasks turnaround time.

Certifications

2016-11

ITIL Foundation

Education

2007-09 -2012-07

Engineer's Degree, Confectionery Industry

Moscow State University of Food Production